Guide to the Christopher Cox Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- William Olander Papers, 1968-1989, undated; Series VIII; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  - Academic papers
    - Research files
      - Outlines and miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 605)
      - Paintings
        - In Paris, undated (Box 40, Folder 606)
        - Individual paintings, 1978-1979 (Box 40, Folder 607)
        - Location unknown, undated (Box 40, Folder 608)
        - Outside Paris, undated (Box 40, Folder 609)
        - Private collections, undated (Box 40, Folder 610)
      - Photographs, 1979, undated (Box 40, Folder 611)
      - Quatremere and education, undated (Box 40, Folder 612)
      - Versailles, undated (Box 40, Folder 613)
  - Professional papers
    - New Museum of Contemporary Art
      - Correspondence and documents, 1985-1988 (Box 40, Folder 614)
      - Exhibition reviews, 1985-1988 (Box 40, Folder 615-616)
    - Other museum exhibition reviews, 1986, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 617)
    - Subject files
      - AIDS and art, 1986-1987, undated (Box 41, Folder 618)
      - Allegory and ideology, undated (Box 41, Folder 619)
      - Clark, T.J., seminar lectures on The Death of Marat, circa 1984 (Box 41, Folder 620)
      - Dalen, Anton van, exhibition catalogue, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 621)
      - Fairy tales: exhibition catalogue, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 622)
      - Feminism, 1987, undated (Box 41, Folder 623)
      - Fey, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 624)
      - Gay art and issues, 1980-1986, undated (Box 41, Folder 625)
      - Group Material, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 626)
      - Guerilla Girls, undated
      - Hudson, performance "World With Out End Amen", 1984
      - Institute on Culture and Society, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 627)
      - Mapplethorpe, Robert, 1980-1988, undated (Box 41, Folder 628)
      - National Association of Artists' Organizations, 1988
      - Notes on media, undated (Box 41, Folder 629)
      - Primitivism, 1984-1985 (Box 41, Folder 630)
      - Theory, undated (Box 41, Folder 631)
      - Video and film, 1975-1987 (Box 41, Folder 632-633)
      - Video announcements and programs, 1985-1987 (Box 41, Folder 634)
      - Yonemoto, Bruce and Norman, interview [audio recording, 90 minutes], circa 1986 (Box 41, Folder 634A)
      - Miscellaneous topics, 1982-1988 (Box 42, Folder 635-637)
  - Writings
    - Articles
      - "Art and Politics of Arms and the Artist," in Art in America, 1985 Jun (Box 42, Folder 638)
      - "Art-as-Ideology at The New Museum," in Art Journal, 1984 winter (Box 42, Folder 639)
      - "Artists View the World Around Them," in Museum, 1981 Nov (Box 42, Folder 640)
      - "Material World," in Art in America, 1989 Jan (Box 42, Folder 641)
      - "The Regionalist Revival," in Dialogue, 1984 Sep (Box 42, Folder 642)
      - "Tales from the Dark Side", undated (Box 42, Folder 643)
      - "What's Wrong with Criticism," in Dialogue, 1984 Jan (Box 42, Folder 644)
    - Book review of Painters and Public Life, in New York Times Book Review, 1986 Mar 9 (Box 42, Folder 645)
    - Essays
      - "An Artistic Agenda" [on LACE], 1986-1988 (Box 42, Folder 646-647)
      - "The Birth of Modern Allegory", 1984-1987 (Box 42, Folder 648-649)
      - "Cumulus", 1987 (Box 42, Folder 650)
      - "Edgar Franceschi: A Painter for the Next Decade", [1988] (Box 43, Folder 651)
      - [Eulogy for Rene], undated (Box 43, Folder 652)
      - "Fake: A Meditation on Authenticity", 1987 (Box 43, Folder 653)
      - "Faking Desire", undated (Box 43, Folder 654)
      - "Homo Video: Where We Are Now", 1986, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 655)
      - "John Glascock and the Simulation of Life", 1983 Sep (Box 43, Folder 656)
      - "A Painter of Modern Life" [on Janet Cooling], 1987 (Box 43, Folder 657)
      - "Robert Mapplethorpe", 1985 (Box 43, Folder 658)
      - "We are unwilling to start down that road", 1986 (Box 43, Folder 659)
      - "Which Brand is for You?", undated (Box 43, Folder 660)
      - "Women and the Media", 1984 (Box 43, Folder 661)
    - Exhibition reviews
      - Disarming Images: Artists' Statements Against Nuclear War, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 662)
      - Ohio exhibitions, in Dialogue and NOVA News, 1980-1982
      - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981, undated (Box 43, Folder 663)
    - Lectures
      - "The Death-of-Painting and the Painting of Death" [on Rudolph Baranik], Columbus, OH, 1986-1987 (Box 43, Folder 664)
      - "Drawing, after Photography," at Alfred, NY, 1986 Mar 12 (Box 43, Folder 665)
      - "French painting and politics in 1794: the great Concours de l'an II," Tallahassee, FL, 1980, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 666)
        Published in 1789: French Art during the Revolution (New York: Colnagi, 1989)
      - "Jacques-Louis David's Death of Bara and the Republic of Virtue in the year 2," at College Art Association, undated (Box 43, Folder 667)
      - [On photography], undated (Box 43, Folder 668)
      - "The Post-Modern Critique of 'Exhibition'", 1986 (Box 43, Folder 669)
      - [Postmodernism or revivalism (re: Walter Benjamin)], at Oberlin, Norfolk, and Toledo, undated (Box 43, Folder 670)
      - [Quality vs. hype], undated (Box 43, Folder 671)
      - "The Recognizable Image: Postmodernism and Photographic Practice," at Boston, New York, and Durham, NH, 1986, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 672-673)
      - "Sherrie Levine: Master of the Game," Atlanta, 1988 Jun 12 (Box 43, Folder 674)
      - [Untitled], at National Association of Artists' Organizations (NAAO) conference, Buffalo, NY, undated (Box 43, Folder 675)
      - Notices of lectures [without texts], 1987, 1988, undated (Box 43, Folder 676)
    - Other writings
      - "Group Material/Anti-Baudrillard," New York, 1987 Jan 25 (Box 43, Folder 677)
      - "Neo-Narratives" [video script], 1983 (Box 43, Folder 678)
      - [On Keith Haring], in Pride Guide '86, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 679)
      - "Visual Obsessions," in Avenue, 1988 Feb (Box 43, Folder 680)
      - "What is Political Art/What is Political Art Now?" in the Village Voice, 1985 Oct 15 (Box 43, Folder 681)
      - [Interview with Marcia Tucker], circa 1988 (Box 43, Folder 682)
    - Other people's writings, 1985, 1987, undated
  - Personal papers
    - AIDS literature, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 683-684)
    - Appointment books, 1979-1988 (Box 44, Folder 685-689)
    - Astrology charts, circa 1980 (Box 44, Folder 690)
    - GMHC newsletters, 1982-1987 (Box 44, Folder 691)
    - Word processing information, and computer disk labeled "Bill resume/video/ memory", 1983, undated (Box 44, Folder 692)
      The computer disk is unreadable.
    - Minneapolis Tribune Sunday magazine, 1968 Aug 11
- Oversize, 3; (2 boxes)
  - Taylor, William (Bill) (in Series I), 1969 Jan 15 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 693)
  - White, Edmund, interviews (in Series I), 1978, 1981 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 694)
  - Nocturnes for the King of Naples (in Series I), 1978 Dec 27 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 695)
  - States of Desire (in Series I), 1979-1980 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 696)
  - Essays and book reviews published in periodicals (in Series I), 1979-1981 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 697)
  - Gadsden (in Series II), 1980 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 698)
  - Pensacola (Gracious Living in Pensacola) (in Series II), undated (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 699)
  - Weathergirl (in Series II), 1980 Jul 9 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 700)
  - "Doe's Pillow," Tent (in Series II), 1979 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 701)
  - Two Gentlemen of Verona, by William Shakespeare (in Series II), 1976 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 702)
  - Witness for the Prosecution, by Agatha Christie (in Series II), 1975 Aug 7 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 703)
  - School newspaper clippings (in Series III), 1965-1966 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 704)
  - Avedon, Richard (in Series VI), 1980 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 705)
  - Capote, Truman (in Series VI), 1967-1976 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 706)
  - Film, Thousand Eyes [magazine] (in Series VI), 1977 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 707)
  - Forest Lawn Memorial Park, Los Angeles (in Series VI), 1927 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 708)
  - Nabokov, Vladimar (in Series VI), 1980 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 709)
  - Ontological Hysteric Theatre (in Series VI), 1977 Dec 22 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 710)
  - Photography (in Series VI), 1976-1978 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 711)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert (in Series VI), 1979 Dec 30 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 712)
  - Sado-masochism (in Series VI), 1975 Jul 7 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 713)
  - Salinger, J.D. (in Series VI), 1975 Jun 23 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 714)
  - Wideman, John Edgar, essay "Language of Home" (in Series VI), 1985 Jan 13 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 715)
  - Wilson, Robert (in Series VI), 1978-1979, undated (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 716)
  - Peruvian newspaper (in Series VI), 1985 Jun 26 (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 717)
  - Colombian newspapers (in Series VI), 1986 Sep (Box 45 (Oversize), Folder 718)
  - Gay art and issues (in Series VIII), 1986-1987 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 719)
  - Guerilla Girls poster (in Series VIII), undated (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 720)
  - Hudson, "World With Out End Amen" (in Series VIII), 1984 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 721)
  - Video and film (in Series VIII), 1975-1987 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 722)
  - Miscellaneous topics: Art Forum issue (in Series VIII), 1985 May (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 723)
  - Book review, of Painters and Public Life (in Series VIII), 1986 Mar 9 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 724)
  - NAAO at LACE (in Series VIII), 1988 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 725)
  - Exhibition reviews in Dialogue and NOVA News (in Series VIII), 1980-1982 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 726-727)
  - Other people's writings (in Series VIII), 1985, 1987, undated (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 728)
  - Minneapolis Tribune Sunday magazine (in Series VIII), 1968 Aug 11 (Box 46 (Oversize), Folder 729)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. (computer disks): Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. (audiocassettes) Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Box 28, folder 457 (Box 47, Folder 730)
  - Box 41, folder 634A (Box 47, Folder 731)
  - Box 44, folder 692 (Box 47, Folder 732)